Papers of James McCaddon
Bridgeport History Center, Bridgeport Public Library
Papers of James McCaddon
1880-1922
1880-1910s
McCaddon, James
BHC-MSS 0008
4 linear feet 1 manuscript box, 2 oversized boxes
Bridgeport History Center, Bridgeport Public Library
One of the key managers for the Barnum and Bailey Circus, the papers of James McCaddon feature personal material from McCaddon's life. They primarily include his memoir, and a number of personal scrapbooks that document family trips and the birth of his son, James McCaddon Junior.
Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Biography
James T. McCaddon was born in Beverly, Ohio on January 31, 1859. Starting as a manager of Adam Forepaugh;s circus, McCaddon went on to become the business manager of the Barnum and Bailey Circus. McCaddon was also the brother-in-law of James A. Bailey by way of James' sister, Ruth, and thus deeply connected to the business by family as well as interest
Scope and Content of Collection
Contains personal life material of James McCaddon. Of note is his memoir, undated, and a number of scrapbooks that contain photographs of family trips and correspondence.
Arrangement
Manuscripts were given priority, with the bulk of the collection focusing on the memoir written in McCaddon's hand. Scrapbooks were separated out from other material, and divided between McCaddon's professional life and personal life.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Barnum, P.T. (Phineas Taylor), 1810-1891; Bailey, James Anthony, 1847-1906; Barnum & London Circus; Barnum and Bailey; Barnum and Bailey - history; Ringling Brothers Barnum and Bailey Circus; Circus- United States - History - 19th century; Circus - United States - History - 20th century
Related Collections
McCaddon Collection of the Barnum and Bailey Circus (TC040), Princeton University. Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections, Manuscript Division. http://arks.princeton.edu/ark:/88435/02870v897
- Inventory
  - Memoir, Index-page 28, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Memoir, 29-239, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memoir, 243-341, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memoir, 349-end, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letterhead for the Estate of James A. Bailey including McCaddon’s name, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dispute of Will of James A. Bailey, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Parish News, Philadelphia, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Program, Liberty Theatre and Gaiety Theatre, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Four Years in Europe: The Barnum and Bailey Greatest Show on Earth in the Old World, 1890-1909 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - National Geographic Magazine, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook, Barnum and Bailey, 1890-1931 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, clippings related to Ruth L. Bailey (1912); Mary McCaddon (1912), Mary McCaddon Larkin (1906), 1906-1912 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, the Baby’s Biography for James McCaddon Jr., 1895 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, Old Cairo, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, McCaddon family, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)